<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prologue on</title><link>/docs/prologue/</link><description>Recent content in Prologue on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/prologue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>/docs/prologue/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/introduction/</guid><description>The PiRogue Tool Suite is an open-source consensual digital forensic analysis and incident response solution that empowers organizations with comprehensive tools for network traffic analysis, mobile forensics, knowledge management, and artifact handling. The tool suite includes both hardware and software components, with the PiRogue network router and its Colander case management platform. Thanks to its open-source and comprehensive nature, its user-friendly design and modular flexibility, its community support, the PiRogue tool suite has become an attractive option for organizations seeking a cost-effective solution for digital investigations.</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>/docs/prologue/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/overview/</guid><description>At the core of the PiRogue Tool Suite lies the PiRogue hardware device, a Raspberry Pi based network router that captures and analyzes network traffic in real-time. This hardware component serves as the foundation for the suite&amp;rsquo;s extensive software capabilities, which include:
Network traffic analysis: The PiRogue enables deep packet inspection of network traffic, facilitating the identification of suspicious patterns and potential threats.
Mobile forensic: The PiRogue allows for the consensual extraction and analysis of data from mobile devices, including messages and application data, providing valuable insights into the system activity.</description></item><item><title>Philosophy</title><link>/docs/prologue/philosophy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/philosophy/</guid><description>We advocate for the democratization of information security tools and threat intelligence, transforming them from exclusive proprietary assets of a select few companies into widely accessible public goods. By embracing open-source principles and fostering collaborative development, we aim to empower individuals and organizations worldwide with the knowledge and tools that are necessary to safeguard their digital assets. Our approach promotes transparency, fosters innovation, and ensures that the benefits of cybersecurity are not confined to a privileged few but are shared among the broader community.</description></item><item><title>Background</title><link>/docs/prologue/background/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/background/</guid><description>PiRogue Tool Suite project is the reboot of the PiRanhaLysis project. PTS is founded by Defensive Lab Agency with the financial support of Open Technology Fund.
Defensive Lab Agency (DLA) is a French company founded in 2018 by Esther Onfroy with the objective of providing expert services on digital security and privacy issues. DLA is specialized in mobile security and focuses its work on supporting NGOs, activists, journalists, human rights defenders and public institutions against digital surveillance.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>/docs/prologue/quick-start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/quick-start/</guid><description>PiRogue # Build your PiRogue →
Alternatively, you can buy a PiRogue from us by reaching out to us.
Colander # In development</description></item></channel></rss>