<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contributors on</title><link>/contributors/</link><description>Recent content in Contributors on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:50:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/contributors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Esther Onfroy</title><link>/contributors/esther-onfroy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:50:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contributors/esther-onfroy/</guid><description>Co-founder and main maintainer at PiRogue Tool Suite.
Expert in information security and reverse engineering, Esther Onfroy aka U039b is a French hacktivist, lecturer and co-founder and main maintainer at PTS. She is also co-founder of Defensive Lab Agency, Exodus Privacy (French non-profit organization that fights against tracking SDKs in Android apps), Pithus (open source mobile threat intelligence platform), Echap (French non-profit organization that fights against the use of technology in violence against women), La Résille (French non-profit organization of hackers producing feminist science-fiction).</description></item><item><title>_lila*</title><link>/contributors/lila/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:50:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contributors/lila/</guid><description>Graphic designer at PiRogue Tool Suite.
Independent illustrator and graphic designer based in Toulouse, Lila is also co-founder of Echap and La Résille. Working through different topics including feminists visions of tech, they’re very interested in how we can build better tools and spaces for our communities.
More details about their activities at https://lila.ink/</description></item><item><title>Christophe Andral</title><link>/contributors/christophe-andral/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:50:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contributors/christophe-andral/</guid><description>Senior software engineer at PiRogue Tool Suite.
A-e.social tech glutton and paradox lover. Freelance the rest of the time.
More details about his activities at https://github.com/TontonSancho</description></item><item><title>Cyril Brulebois</title><link>/contributors/cyril-brulebois/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 14:26:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contributors/cyril-brulebois/</guid><description>Debian expert at PiRogue Tool Suite.
Cyril embraced the Debian project two decades ago, moving through various roles: user, translator, package maintainer, release team member, and release manager for the installation system.
Based in Dijon, he provides his expertise on Debian topics internationally through DEBAMAX.</description></item></channel></rss>