<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Colander on</title><link>/docs/colander/</link><description>Recent content in Colander on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/colander/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>/docs/colander/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/colander/overview/</guid><description>Colander web platform is a case and incident response management platform that integrates seamlessly with the hardware and software components. Colander provides a centralized hub for managing investigations, streamlining workflows, and enabling effective collaboration among team members.
Knowledge management: Colander facilitates the organization and sharing of investigative knowledge, ensuring that insights are readily available to team members, promoting collaboration and efficiency.
Artifact management: Colander streamlines the handling and preservation of digital evidence, maintaining chain of custody and ensuring admissibility in legal proceedings.</description></item><item><title>Architecture</title><link>/docs/colander/architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/colander/architecture/</guid><description>Colander relies on different services:
colander-postgres: Postgres database colander-front: Gunicorn serving the pages of Colander colander-worker: Django Q2 cluster of workers traefik: Traefik reverse proxy ensuring TLS termination and routing cyberchef: CyberChef instance playwright: service using Playwright to take URL screenshot and capture the HAR elasticsearch: single node ElasticSearch server storing network traffic analysis minio: Minio S3-compatible object storage to store artifacts redis: Redis server ensuring the communication between the front and the workers for both Colander and Threatr watchtower: Watchtower service keeping the stack up to date Colander comes with Threatr which relies on:</description></item><item><title>Graphical interface</title><link>/docs/colander/graphical-interface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/colander/graphical-interface/</guid><description>The graphical interface of Colander allows to navigate through the different workspaces as well as easily switching from one case to another or quickly searching for entities within a selected case or within all the user’s cases.
The graphical interface changes depending on a case as been selected or not. When no case is selected, the quick search bar will apply to all the cases the user has access to. In this mode, only 2 workspaces are accessible:</description></item><item><title>Case and knowledge management</title><link>/docs/colander/case-and-knowledge-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/colander/case-and-knowledge-management/</guid><description>In the context of digital investigation, the effective organization and management of cases are imperative. As a digital investigator you focus on documenting incident, the utilization of Colander serves as a comprehensive platform to streamline and document investigative efforts. This document explain how to use Colander for organizing and managing digital investigation cases.
Case management # Case management is the overarching framework that organizes and oversees the entire digital investigation process, from the initial identification of a potential crime or incident to the final report and resolution.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge graph</title><link>/docs/colander/knowledge-graph/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/colander/knowledge-graph/</guid><description>In the realm of digital investigations, where the volume and complexity of data can be overwhelming, knowledge graphs emerge as a sophisticated tool for organizing, analyzing, and extracting meaningful insights. These structured representations of knowledge, akin to semantic networks, connect entities and their interrelationships, providing a cohesive framework for comprehending the intricacies of digital environments.
At the heart of knowledge graphs lies a network of interconnected nodes, each representing a distinct entity.</description></item><item><title>🚧 External sources</title><link>/docs/colander/external-sources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/colander/external-sources/</guid><description/></item><item><title>🚧 Collaboration</title><link>/docs/colander/collaboration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/colander/collaboration/</guid><description/></item><item><title>🚧 Artifact management</title><link>/docs/colander/artifact-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/colander/artifact-management/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chain of custody</title><link>/docs/colander/chain-of-custody/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/colander/chain-of-custody/</guid><description>In the intricate domain of digital forensics, maintaining confidentiality is paramount to protect sensitive information and ensure the integrity of investigations. Two widely adopted confidentiality frameworks, Traffic Light Protocol (TLP) and Permissible Actions Protocol (PAP), provide structured guidelines for sharing and restricting access to sensitive data. These frameworks empower digital forensic practitioners to navigate the delicate balance between information sharing and confidentiality.
TLP &amp;amp; PAP # The Traffic Light Protocol (TLP) employs a color-coded system to classify information and guide its dissemination:</description></item><item><title>Network traffic decryption</title><link>/docs/colander/network-traffic-decryption/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/colander/network-traffic-decryption/</guid><description>Have a look to the guide dedicated to network traffic decryption →</description></item></channel></rss>