<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recipes on</title><link>/docs/recipes/</link><description>Recent content in Recipes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PiRogue without ethernet connection</title><link>/docs/recipes/pirogue-without-ethernet-connection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/recipes/pirogue-without-ethernet-connection/</guid><description>This is the translation in English of a tutorial originally written by Thomas Fourmeux, a French librarian. Follow him on Twitter!
Context # This tutorial is for using the PiRogue in a situation where you don&amp;rsquo;t have a wired connection to the Internet (such as in a car). Thanks to a travel router, you will be able to share (via USB) your smartphone&amp;rsquo;s LTE/4G connection with the PiRogue.
Requirements # In this situation, you need the following hardware:</description></item><item><title>Device forensic with MVT</title><link>/docs/recipes/device-forensic-with-mvt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/recipes/device-forensic-with-mvt/</guid><description>Disclaimer # Mobile Verification Toolkit (MVT) is a tool to facilitate the consensual forensic analysis of Android and iOS devices, for the purpose of identifying traces of compromise.
MVT&amp;rsquo;s purpose is not to facilitate adversarial forensics of non-consenting individuals&amp;rsquo; devices. The use of MVT and derivative products to extract and/or analyse data originating from devices used by individuals not consenting to the procedure is explicitly prohibited in the license.
MVT a.</description></item><item><title>Add your own suricata rules to PiRogue</title><link>/docs/recipes/add-your-own-suricata-rules-to-pirogue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/recipes/add-your-own-suricata-rules-to-pirogue/</guid><description>This is a friendly contribution written by evilcel3ri, security researcher also developer for Pithus. Follow him on Twitter!
Add your own suricata rules to PiRogue # You need:
SSH access to your PiRogue Github knowledge Optional: if you want access to ET PRO you would need your Oink code The easiest way to manage your Suricata rules is to have them on a Github repository or on a Web directory that can be checked out by suricata-update.</description></item><item><title>Turn a regular PC into a PiRogue</title><link>/docs/recipes/turn-a-regular-pc-into-a-pirogue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/recipes/turn-a-regular-pc-into-a-pirogue/</guid><description>This recipe is dedicated to intrepid users 😎
Requirements # To follow this recipe we need:
a PC with one Ethernet interface, one wireless interface and Debian 11 freshly installed the wireless interface has to support the AP mode (access-point mode) the PC is connected to our local network via its Ethernet adapter the PC has an Internet connection ⚠️ Don&amp;rsquo;t install any desktop environment. Prepare the system # We will do everything by command line so, we connect to our PC and run the following command to upgrade it:</description></item><item><title>How to intercept and decrypt TLS traffic</title><link>/docs/recipes/how-to-intercept-and-decrypt-tls-traffic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/recipes/how-to-intercept-and-decrypt-tls-traffic/</guid><description>This recipe is dedicated to intrepid users 😎
PiRogue comes with a pirogue-intercept-* helpers to help you intercept encrypted TLS traffic from applications, even in presence of TLS certificate pinning.
These helpers are meant to:
capture the network traffic instrument a specific application or any launched application Requirements # To follow this recipe, you need:
an up-to-date PiRogue a rooted Android device Procedure # First, SSH onto your PiRogue. Attach your smartphone to the PiRogue through USB and make sure &amp;ldquo;USB debugging&amp;rdquo; is on and working.</description></item><item><title>Export PiRogue data</title><link>/docs/recipes/export-pirogue-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/recipes/export-pirogue-data/</guid><description>This is the translation in English from Spanish of a tutorial originally written by niculcha.
What is PiRogue # For a few months we have been testing PiRogue to perform network traffic analysis mainly on cell phones, so PiRogue becomes a super complete tool that contains many applications that help us to perform network traffic analysis, this hardware and software helps us to perform monitoring on intervention and network traffic.</description></item></channel></rss>