<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Training material on</title><link>/guides/</link><description>Recent content in Training material on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beginner guide - How to setup a PiRogue</title><link>/guides/g1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/guides/g1/</guid><description>PiRogue tool suite (PTS) is an open-source tool suite that provides a comprehensive mobile forensic and network traffic analysis platform targeting mobile devices both Android and iOS, internet of things devices (devices that are connected to the user mobile apps), and in general any device using wi-fi to connect to the Internet.
Main PiRogue capabilities # The PiRogue is an open hardware device based on a Raspberry Pi operating as a network router (like any ISP router) analyzing network traffic in real time.</description></item><item><title>Beginner guide - How to capture and analyze device's network traffic</title><link>/guides/g2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/guides/g2/</guid><description>To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s explain first what we are doing here:
We will be using the PiRogue as a network router. A network router is a device that facilitates communication between the internet and the devices in your home that connect to the internet. As its name implies, it &amp;ldquo;routes&amp;rdquo; traffic between devices and other networks, such as the internet. The PiRogue functions similarly to your ISP&amp;rsquo;s router, allowing you to connect from one network to another by plugging it into the router using an Ethernet cable.</description></item><item><title>⌛ Beginner guide - How to handle a potentially malicious mobile app</title><link>/guides/g3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/guides/g3/</guid><description>On a daily basis, we encounter potentially malicious applications in various forms. They can appear as seemingly harmless apps we intend to download from Google Play (although it&amp;rsquo;s rare &amp;ndash; Google usually takes them down), or they may be disguised as links or APK files shared within chat groups, especially if we are human rights defenders operating in a high-surveillance environment. Additionally, these malicious applications can be found on compromised devices.</description></item><item><title>⌛ Beginner guide - How to backup a mobile device for forensic analysis purpose</title><link>/guides/g4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/guides/g4/</guid><description>Coming soon</description></item><item><title>⌛ Intermediate guide - How to use tools such as Pithus or APKLab to conduct mobile app static analysis</title><link>/guides/g5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/guides/g5/</guid><description>Coming soon</description></item><item><title>⌛ Intermediate guide - How to use MVT to conduct the analysis of a mobile device and its backup image</title><link>/guides/g6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/guides/g6/</guid><description>Coming soon</description></item><item><title>⌛ Intermediate guide - How to handle a potentially compromised device</title><link>/guides/g7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/guides/g7/</guid><description>Coming soon</description></item><item><title>⌛ Advanced guide - How to use PTS to intercept the TLS and cleartext network traffic of an app</title><link>/guides/g8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/guides/g8/</guid><description>Coming soon</description></item><item><title>⌛ Advanced guide - How to use PTS to analyze the network traffic of an app to expose potential data collection or data exfiltration</title><link>/guides/g9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/guides/g9/</guid><description>Coming soon</description></item><item><title>⌛ Comprehensive guide into case management and incident response</title><link>/guides/g10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/guides/g10/</guid><description>Coming soon</description></item></channel></rss>