<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The PiRogue on</title><link>/docs/pirogue/</link><description>Recent content in The PiRogue on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/pirogue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>/docs/pirogue/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/overview/</guid><description>What a PiRogue is # The PiRogue is an open hardware device based on a Raspberry Pi operating as a network router (like any ISP router) analyzing network traffic in real time.
It can operate in different modes:
an on-the-field mode
for emergency response (active spying, device tampering, &amp;hellip;) useful for responders in repressive environment conduct forensics analysis and network detection using a pre-installed set of tools an expert mode for technical people to:</description></item><item><title>Build a PiRogue</title><link>/docs/pirogue/build-a-pirogue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/build-a-pirogue/</guid><description>The hardware you need # In addition to a computer and an Internet connection, you will need, at least, a Raspberry Pi (+ its power supply), a SD-card and an ethernet cable.
Pick a Raspberry Pi # First, you need a Raspberry Pi. We support the following versions of Raspberry Pi:
Raspberry Pi 3 Model B Raspberry Pi 3 Model B+ Raspberry Pi 4 Model B - 1GB Raspberry Pi 4 Model B - 2GB Raspberry Pi 4 Model B - 4GB Raspberry Pi 4 Model B - 8GB Important note: Suricata is disabled on devices having less then 1.</description></item><item><title>Build a PiRogue hat</title><link>/docs/pirogue/build-a-pirogue-hat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/build-a-pirogue-hat/</guid><description>The current PiRogue case version is v1.0_beta.
Get the KiCad project and manufacturing files on GitHub →
👉 Precision regarding some parts:
the 2x20 header has to be in the tall version, you can buy one from Adafruit use a SPI 240x240 IPS screen like this one use CR1220 battery Overview #</description></item><item><title>Build a PiRogue case</title><link>/docs/pirogue/build-a-pirogue-case/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/build-a-pirogue-case/</guid><description>The current PiRogue case version is v1.0_beta.
Get the manufacturing files on GitHub →
3D print a PiRogue case # To 3D print your PiRogue case, you will need:
either the 4 separate STL files or the one containing the 4 part ready the slice a 3D printer PLA or PETG Recommended printing parameters # layer height: 0.2 mm infill: 20% no support material: PETG The entire printing lasts around 3 hours for a complete case.</description></item><item><title>Configure a PiRogue</title><link>/docs/pirogue/configure-a-pirogue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/configure-a-pirogue/</guid><description>⚠️ This documentation requires either
the package pirogue-base version 1.0.2 or more recent being installed the package pirogue-base-pc version 1.0.0 or more recent being installed Not sure? Upgrade your PiRogue.
How the PiRogue configuration works # PiRogue features come in Debian packages, each package manages some system configuration files:
the package pirogue-ap creates the wi-fi access point, it manages: /etc/hostapd/hostapd.conf /etc/dnsmasq.conf /etc/dhcpcd.conf /etc/iptables/rules.v4 /etc/iptables/rules.v6 the package pirogue-dashboard creates the dashboard, it manages: /etc/grafana/grafana.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade a PiRogue</title><link>/docs/pirogue/upgrade-a-pirogue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/upgrade-a-pirogue/</guid><description>All PiRogue features are bundled in Debian packages. So, by upgrading Debian (which is the only supported operating system) you are also upgrading your PiRogue.
To upgrade both the OS and the PiRogue features, run the following two commands:
sudo apt update sudo apt dist-upgrade This operation could take some time and would require a reboot to make your PiRogue operates properly.
How often should I upgrade my PiRogue # We advice you to upgrade your PiRogue weekly.</description></item><item><title>Operate a PiRogue</title><link>/docs/pirogue/operate-a-pirogue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/operate-a-pirogue/</guid><description>Find your PiRogue on the network # Once your PiRogue is running, it will be accessible to you from the network. There are 2 ways to get the IP address of your PiRogue.
The first way is by looking at the screen of the PiRogue Hat.
The second way is to use the ping command. To do so, on your computer connected to the same network as your PiRogue, run the following command:</description></item><item><title>Cheatsheet</title><link>/docs/pirogue/cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/cheatsheet/</guid><description>Default configuration # Name Value Example of usage SSH port 22 ssh -p22 pi@&amp;lt;PiRogue IP address&amp;gt; SSH user pi SSH password raspberry Dashboard port 3000 http://&amp;lt;PiRogue IP address&amp;gt;:3000 Dashboard user admin Dashboard password PiRogue Wi-Fi SSID PiRogue1 Wi-Fi password superlongkey Chronograph port 8888 http://&amp;lt;PiRogue IP address&amp;gt;:8888 To see your configuration, run
sudo pirogue-ctl config show Important files # Name Location SSH configuration /etc/ssh/sshd_config PiRogue configuration /var/lib/pirogue/config/pirogue.env Suricata rules /var/lib/suricata/rules/suricata.rules</description></item><item><title>Useful commands</title><link>/docs/pirogue/useful-commands/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/useful-commands/</guid><description>Find the IP address of your PiRogue # On your computer connected to the same network as your PiRogue, run the following command:
ping -c1 pirogue.local Example of output, in this example, the IP address of the PiRogue is 192.168.0.16:
PING pirogue.local (192.168.0.16) 56(84) bytes of data. 64 bytes from pirogue.home (192.168.0.16): icmp_seq=1 ttl=64 time=0.319 ms --- pirogue.local ping statistics --- 1 packets transmitted, 1 received, 0% packet loss, time 0ms rtt min/avg/max/mdev = 0.</description></item><item><title>Pre-installed tools</title><link>/docs/pirogue/pre-installed-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/pre-installed-tools/</guid><description>Your PiRogue comes with a set a pre-installed and pre-configured tools covering different purposes.
Network traffic capture # tcpdump to capture network traffic into PCAP files - documentation mitm-proxy to intercept and capture HTTPS traffic - documentation Network traffic analysis # suricata to detect malicious traffic based on rules - documentation nfstream to inspect traffic and determine the application involved in each flow - documentation Device analysis &amp;amp; forensic # adb to interact with Android devices - documentation libimobiledevice to interact with iOS devices - documentation mvt to conduct device forensic analysis - documentation frida to instrument programs running on a device - documentation Data visualization # influxdb to store data generated by nfstream and suricata - documentation chronograph to search and export data stored in influxdb - documentation grafana to display data on dashboards - documentation Utilities # vim to edit files - documentation git to version files - documentation jq to manipulate JSON files - documentation gnupg2 to sign, encrypt and verify files - documentation python3 to write and execute Python programs - documentation</description></item></channel></rss>