<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PiRogue on</title><link>/docs/pirogue/</link><description>Recent content in PiRogue on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/pirogue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>/docs/pirogue/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/overview/</guid><description>The PiRogue The PiRogue is a Raspberry Pi-based network router that captures and analyses network traffic in real-time. This hardware component serves as the foundation for the suite&amp;rsquo;s extensive software capabilities, which include:
Network traffic analysis: The PiRogue enables deep packet inspection of network traffic, facilitating the identification of suspicious patterns and potential threats.
Mobile forensic: The PiRogue allows for the consensual extraction and analysis of data from mobile devices, including messages, and application data, providing valuable insights into user activity.</description></item><item><title>Architecture</title><link>/docs/pirogue/architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/architecture/</guid><description>The PiRogue network router acts as a packet inspection system (PIS) that is used to detect potentially malicious network traffic of any device connected to its Wi-Fi access-point. It relies on the following components:
NFStream: This component is responsible for capturing and parsing network traffic. It can capture traffic from a variety of sources, including physical interfaces, virtual interfaces, and network taps. NFStream also supports a variety of packet capture formats, including pcap, pcapng, and AF_PACKET.</description></item><item><title>Hardware</title><link>/docs/pirogue/hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/hardware/</guid><description>The PiRogue&amp;rsquo;s core hardware consists of a Raspberry Pi 4, a versatile single-board computer, enhanced with a custom-designed HAT (Hardware Attachment on Top). This HAT serves as an expansion board that seamlessly integrates with the Raspberry Pi, providing additional functionalities and enhancing its capabilities. It features a TFT screen, a Real-Time Clock (RTC), and cooling fan control circuitry.
PiRogue HAT # The SPI TFT screen acts as a visual interface, displaying crucial information such as system status, network activity, and security alerts.</description></item><item><title>Operating system</title><link>/docs/pirogue/operating-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/operating-system/</guid><description>The PiRogue runs PiRogueOS which is based on Debian 12 by the time we are writing this document (Dec. 2023). Debian is a renowned Linux distribution recognized for its stability, reliability, and commitment to open-source principles. It serves as a foundational platform for numerous other distributions and is widely adopted in various industries, including enterprise environments, scientific research, and embedded systems. Debian&amp;rsquo;s trustworthiness stems from its long-standing reputation for quality, its rigorous testing and development processes, and its commitment to open and transparent collaboration.</description></item><item><title>Telemetry</title><link>/docs/pirogue/telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/telemetry/</guid><description>Why? # The telemetry is used to measure the adoption of the project, but also to get some information about the hardware used and thus anticipate the support of widely used but not yet fully supported hardware. Telemetry data is collected on a daily basis.
The collected data is stored for a year on a server managed by us, hosted by Hetzner in Germany.
How to opt-out # You can use the command</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>/docs/pirogue/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/configuration/</guid><description>⚠️ This documentation requires either
the package pirogue-base version 1.0.2 or more recent being installed the package pirogue-base-pc version 1.0.0 or more recent being installed Not sure? Upgrade your PiRogue.
How the PiRogue configuration works # PiRogue features come in Debian packages, each package manages some system configuration files:
the package pirogue-ap creates the wi-fi access point, it manages: /etc/hostapd/hostapd.conf /etc/dnsmasq.conf /etc/dhcpcd.conf /etc/iptables/rules.v4 /etc/iptables/rules.v6 the package pirogue-dashboard creates the dashboard, it manages: /etc/grafana/grafana.</description></item><item><title>Network traffic analysis</title><link>/docs/pirogue/network-traffic-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/network-traffic-analysis/</guid><description>The PiRogue is designed to continuously analyze the network traffic of any device connected to its Wi-Fi network. This means that it is constantly monitoring and inspecting the data packets that are being transmitted and received by these devices. The purpose of this analysis is to identify any suspicious or malicious activity that may be taking place on the device.
The PiRogue employs two primary methods for analyzing network traffic: NFStream Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) and Suricata rule-based IDS.</description></item><item><title>Dashboard</title><link>/docs/pirogue/dashboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/dashboard/</guid><description>By default, the PiRogue exposes a Grafana dashboard at the address http://pirogue.local:3000 showing in real-time the ongoing network connections, security alerts and other information. The default dashboard is composed of different panels.
Overview of the PiRogue dashboard Have a look to the guide dedicated to the PiRogue dashboard →
General statistics # General statistics panel provides a comprehensive overview of network activity and security events within the selected timeframe. It presents a detailed breakdown of the following metrics:</description></item><item><title>Export data</title><link>/docs/pirogue/export-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/export-data/</guid><description>PiRogue deletes the data every 5 days for security reasons but to do a further analysis it is necessary to extract the alerts and flows as a result of the analysis, to export the data we need to do the following steps.
Once connected to the PiRogue, run the command
$ influx -database &amp;#39;suricata&amp;#39; -execute &amp;#39;SELECT * FROM &amp;#34;suricata&amp;#34;.&amp;#34;suricata_5d&amp;#34;.&amp;#34;alert&amp;#34;&amp;#39; -format &amp;#39;csv&amp;#39; alerts-`date +&amp;#34;%Y-%m-%d&amp;#34;`.csv to export all Suricata alerts in a CSV file.</description></item><item><title>Consensual device forensic</title><link>/docs/pirogue/consensual-device-forensic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/pirogue/consensual-device-forensic/</guid><description>Consensual mobile device forensic analysis is the process of examining a mobile device with the owner&amp;rsquo;s consent to identify signs of compromise or active spying. This involves analyzing data stored on the device, such as call logs, text messages, and browsing history, as well as examining installed apps and system configurations. The goal is to uncover any unauthorized access, surveillance activities, or malicious software that may be compromising the device&amp;rsquo;s security and privacy.</description></item></channel></rss>